🗹 karltallon98@gmail.com 📞 -

+353838495128



Dublin, Ireland

#### **SUMMARY**

I'm a Full Stack Developer with over half a decade of professional experience, proficient in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, & React. Seeking to use my technical proficiency & creativity while collaborating with enthusiastic teams to develop unique products.

## **EXPERIENCE**

# AnDAPT | Semiconductors | B2B, B2C, Saas | www.andapt.com

Nov 2022 - Present

- Full Stack Developer
- Spearheaded redesign of AnDAPT's website in an **agile** team as the lead developer, utilising tools such as **HTML**, **CSS**, **JavaScript**, & **PHP**, implementing fully **responsive designs**, optimising **SEO**, improving **Google Analytics 4** & **AWS** configuration, establishing **testing** protocols, & boosting **website performance** metrics by over 40% on average.
- Utilised **Figma** to wireframe new website content for AnDAPT product releases, operating as the lead **UX** designer.
- Identified & **debugged** major **MySQL** security vulnerabilities to improve reliability, security, & maintainability of the system. Documented the process for future reference across the organisation.
- Collaborated with stakeholders to develop a tailored **ERP/CRM** system, streamlining operations, increasing lead generation, centralising information, & establishing universal data formats for the global sales team.

# Lotus Web Designs | Web Development | B2B, B2C

Sept 2021 - Nov 2022

Freelance Developer

- Founded a freelance company creating unique websites for numerous clients, utilising technologies including JavaScript & React.js, as well as CMS platforms such as WordPress & Wix to transform client requirements into custom designs that met deadlines & exceeded client expectations.
- Remained updated on industry advancements, producing cohesive visual styles & structures for all client websites for a modern & professional appearance.

# Flowte | E-Ticketing Platform | B2B, B2C, Saas | www.flowte.com

Sept 2020 - July 2021

Software Engineer

- Collaborated with development team to create Flowte's website, utilising technologies such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, WordPress, AWS & Figma.
- Led **MySQL** database migration project to modernise Flowte's database architecture for current industry standards within a **scrum** team.
- Gained indepth software development experience in code reviews, CI/CD testing, technical support, product development, marketing strategies, & Zoho CRM.

## **SKILLS**

### **Frontend Skills**

- HTML/CSS
- JavaScript
- React.js
- Next.js
- Bootstrap
- Tailwind
- Material-UI
- Framer

# **Backend Skills**

- Node.js
- PHP
- XML
- MySQL
- ReduxNPM
- NPM
- CI/CD Testing
- Debugging

#### **Tools**

- AWS
- Cloudflare
- GitHub
- Figma
- Sketch
- Adobe XD
- Adobe Photoshop
- WordPress
- Wix

#### Competencies

- Responsive Design
- UI/UX Design
- Cross Browser Compatibility
- Accessibility Standards
- Mobile-first Development Practices
- Web Performance Optimisation
- SEO Optimisation
- Version Control Systems
- Agile/Scrum Methodology

## **EDUCATION**

## National College of Ireland

2018 - 2022

BSc. (Hons) Computer Science

- First Class Honours 3.8/4.0 GPA
- Dean's Honour Award Recipient 2020-2022
- Vice President of eSports & Gaming Society 2018-2020

# REFERENCES

#### Giovanni Garcea

President of AnDAPT

Email: giovanni.garcea@andapt.com

Hugh O'Morain

CEO of Flowte

Email: hugh@flowte.com

## **WEBSITES**

www.karltallon.com

www.github.com/Tallon1

in www.linkedin.com/in/karl-tallon

# **LANGUAGES**

- English (Native Speaker/Fluent)
- Japanese (Classroom Study)